- Are you ready, kids?
- 孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- I can't hear you.
- 我听不到你说话。
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- ♪ Ohh... ♪
- ♪ 哦...♪
♪ Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? ♪
♪ 谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ ♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he ♪
- ♪ 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的 ♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ If nautical nonsense
be something you wish ♪
- ♪ 如果航海废话
成为你想要的东西♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish ♪
- ♪ 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通♪
all: SpongeBob SquarePants!
- Ready?
所有：海绵宝宝！
- 准备好？
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob SquarePants!
- SpongeBob
- 海绵宝宝
SquarePants!
方裤！
[laughing]
[笑]
♪ ♪
[waves crashing]
[海浪拍打]
[buoyant music]
[轻快的音乐]
♪ ♪
- [yawns] Whoa.
- [哈欠] 哇哦。
- [high-pitched grumbling] Oh!
- [高声抱怨]哦！
- [snoring]
- [打鼾]
Huh?
啊？
[whimpers] Ma? Pa?
[呜咽]妈？爸？
[sobbing]
[抽泣]
- I'm Gale Doppler
with the big weather!
- 我是盖尔·多普勒
随着大天气！
Well just as I predicted,
those severe thunderstorms
嗯，正如我所预料的那样，
那些猛烈的雷暴
are moving to the southeast,
and I guarantee
正在向东南方向移动，
我保证
it's gonna be nothing
but sunny skies
不会有事的
但天空晴朗
for the rest of the week.
本周剩下的时间。
This is Gale Doppler,
and I broadcast
这是大风多普勒，
我广播
the forecast
that's never wrong!
预测
那永远不会错！
Heh heh.
呵呵。
- [panting] Huh?
- [气喘吁吁] 啊？
[muttering]
[嘀咕]
Whoa--boing!
Hah!
哇——呸！
哈！
Sunny skies all week?
整个星期天气晴朗？
Hot diggity!
[mutters]
热数字！
[嘀咕]
[hums] Ah.
[哼哼]啊。
Rain.
雨。
But--but
但是——但是
Gale Doppler
is never wrong.
大风多普勒
永远不会错。
Huh? Hm.
啊？嗯。
[mumbles] What...?
[咕哝]什么……？
- [sobbing]
- Hm?
- [抽泣]
- 嗯？
Aw, it's a little baby
storm cloud.
哇，是个小宝宝
风暴云。
Hello, little cloud.
Nice to meet you.
你好，小云。
很高兴见到你。
- [weeping]
- [哭泣]
- Oh, you're crying.
I thought you were raining.
- 哦，你在哭。
我还以为你下雨了
- Huh?
- 啊？
[whimpering]
[呜咽]
- Oh, now don't be scared.
- 哦，现在别害怕。
SpongeBob knows just what
a growing storm cloud needs.
海绵宝宝知道什么
不断增长的风暴云需求。
Huhh. Hot steam.
呵呵。热蒸汽。
[kisses]
[亲吻]
Mm. Hm-hm-hm-hmm.
Mm-hmm.
毫米。嗯-嗯-嗯-嗯。
嗯嗯。
- [whimpers]
- [呜咽]
[enthusiastic muttering]
[热情的嘀咕]
[slurping]
[发出声音]
[sighs]
[叹气]
Huh?
[whimpers]
啊？
[呜咽]
- Well, okay,
I don't see any clouds,
- 嗯，好吧，
我看不到任何云彩
so I'm just gonna take a walk.
- Huh?
所以我要去散步。
- 啊？
- [whistling]
- [吹口哨]
Tut, tut, it looks like rain.
啧啧，看来要下雨了。
Hah!
哈！
Oh, hello there.
哦，你好。
Aw, who's a cute cumulous?
哦，谁是可爱的积木？
I always wanted to have
a pet cloud formation.
我一直想拥有
宠物云的形成。
I'm gonna name you...
我会给你起名字...
[gasps] Drizzle.
[喘气]毛毛雨。
[giggling] Whoo.
[咯咯笑] 哇。
Whoo--
呼——
- [babbling]
- [胡言乱语]
- Hey, good visibility!
- 嘿，能见度好！
[muttering]
[嘀咕]
[laughs]
- [inhaling]
[笑]
- [吸气]
- Wha! Oh.
- 世界卫生大会！哦。
And gusty winds
from the southeast.
还有狂风
从东南方向。
[both laughing]
[两人都笑了]
- [beeping]
- Um.
- [嘟嘟声]
- 嗯。
A clam eating a telephone.
一只蛤蜊正在吃电话。
- [pop]
- A fur chandelier!
- [流行音乐]
- 毛皮吊灯！
A lamp! A shoe factory!
一盏灯！鞋厂！
A continental breakfast!
欧陆式早餐！
- Ooh.
- A chicken!
- 哦。
- 一只鸡！
- [clucks]
- Oh, I am so good at this.
- [咯咯笑]
- 哦，我很擅长这个。
[humming]
[嗡嗡声]
- [sniffing]
- [嗅嗅]
[both snarl]
[双方咆哮]
- [barking]
- [straining]
- [吠叫]
- [紧张]
- [screeches]
- [尖叫声]
- Sorry. Ee...
- 对不起。呃……
Bad Drizzle. Bad.
糟糕的毛毛雨。坏的。
- [whimpers]
- [呜咽]
Well, all right, not that bad.
嗯，好吧，没那么糟糕。
Okay, let's go home.
好吧，我们回家吧。
- [panting]
- [giggles]
- [气喘吁吁]
- [咯咯笑]
I'm sorry Drizzle,
but you can't go in the house
对不起，小雨，
但你不能进屋
until you're housebroken.
直到你家破人亡。
- [meows]
- [喵]
- I'll check on you later.
- 我稍后会查看你的情况。
- [whimpers, straining]
- [呜咽，紧张]
[continues straining]
[继续紧张]
[thunder booming]
[雷霆轰鸣]
[lightning crackles]
[闪电爆裂声]
Whoo-hoo!
呼呼！
- It's later!
- 稍后！
Who wants a steaming hot bowl
of steam?
谁想要一碗热气腾腾的
蒸汽？
Ah! Drizzle!
啊!细雨！
Yow! Hot, hot, hot, hot, hot!
哟！热，热，热，热，热！
Where art thou, Drizzle?
小雨，你在哪里？
Oh, what unfortunate forecast
be this.
噢，多么不幸的预测啊
是这个。
[whimpers]--oh wait,
there he goes.
[呜咽]——哦等等，
他就在那里。
Come back, Drizzle!
回来吧，小雨！
[wailing] Come back!
[哀嚎]回来吧！
- Whoa!
- 哇！
- Oh, get off the road!
- 哦，离开马路！
[horn blaring]
[喇叭声]
- [wailing, groaning]
- [哀号，呻吟]
[shrieking]
[尖叫]
[rumbling]
[隆隆声]
[snails hissing]
[蜗牛嘶嘶声]
[panicked yelling]
[惊慌失措的叫喊]
- It's raining snails
and worms!
- 下着蜗牛雨
还有蠕虫！
[thud]
[panicked wailing]
[砰]
[惊慌的哀号]
- That's impossible!
- 那是不可能的！
I called for sunny skies
and for 35 years
我呼唤晴朗的天空
35年来
I broadcast the forecast
that's never wrong.
我广播了天气预报
那永远不会错。
[both growling]
[双方咆哮]
[blows landing, hissing]
[吹气着陆，嘶嘶声]
- This just in:
Gale Doppler is wrong!
- 这只是在：
大风多普勒是错误的！
- [laughs awkwardly]
Huh?
- [尴尬地笑]
啊？
[panicked yelling]
[zapping]
[惊慌失措的叫喊]
[电击]
[grunts] Ah! I see the trouble
now, folks.
[咕哝]啊！我看到了麻烦
现在，伙计们。
That is what they call
an unpredictable storm front.
这就是他们所说的
不可预测的风暴锋
But don't worry.
但不用担心。
[whirring]
[呼呼]
I'm gonna suck him
right out of the sky
我要吸他
就在天上
to save my reputation,
after these messages.
为了挽救我的名誉，
在这些消息之后。
- Are you constipated?
- 你便秘吗？
Sure, we all are.
当然，我们都是。
Thank goodness there's new--
- Drizzle!
谢天谢地，又有新的了——
- 毛毛雨！
Drizzle, where are you?
Excuse me.
细雨，你在哪里？
打扰一下。
Have you seen a little storm
cloud about yea big?
你见过一场小风暴吗
云大约有多大？
[all screaming]
[所有人尖叫]
- [whimpering]
- [呜咽]
Ah!
啊!
[whimpering]
[呜咽]
[whirring]
[呼呼]
[straining]
- I got him!
[紧张]
- 我抓到他了！
Naughty nimbus, nobody messes
with my flawless forecasts.
顽皮的雨云，没人惹事
和我完美的预测。
It's back to sunny skies
for Bikini Bottom.
又回到了晴朗的天空
比基尼泳裤。
- Drizzle! Drizzle!
- 毛毛雨！细雨！
Drizzle!
细雨！
Oh, there you are, Drizzle.
[gasps]
噢，你来了，小雨。
[喘气]
Gale Doppler!
强风多普勒！
You're my favorite
wall-eyed weather man!
你是我的最爱
目光短浅的天气预报员！
Oh, thanks for finding
my lost pet, Mr. Doppler.
哦，谢谢你找到了
我丢失的宠物，多普勒先生。
Time to go home, Drizzle.
是时候回家了，小雨。
- I'm sorry, square face.
- 对不起，方脸。
This cloud is a danger
to the public.
这朵云是危险的
向公众。
And I'm sending him straight
to cloud heaven.
我直接发给他
到云天。
- [whimpering]
[whirring]
- [呜咽]
[呼呼]
- [gasps]
- [喘气]
- [whimpering, wails]
- [呜咽，哀号]
- [laughs]
- [笑]
I'm Gale Doppler,
我是盖尔·多普勒
and I con-trol the weather.
我控制天气。
[laughing]
- Hey, Doppler.
[笑]
- 嘿，多普勒。
You're not the only one
who knows
你不是唯一一个
谁知道
how to use a leaf blower,
sucker.
如何使用吹叶机，
傻瓜。
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
- Huh?
- 啊？
Hm. Blah!
嗯。废话！
- Hm? [snarls]
- 嗯？ [咆哮]
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
- Hm? Aha!
- 嗯？啊哈！
- Huh?
- [panting]
- 啊？
- [气喘吁吁]
[mysterious music]
[神秘的音乐]
- Huh? Ah.
- Ah!
- 啊？啊。
- 啊！
Yah-whoo-ah!
啊呼啊！
We did it, Drizzle.
我们做到了，细雨。
We put a stoppler
to the doppler.
我们放了一个塞子
到多普勒。
And I predict sunny skies
for the rest of our lives.
我预测晴空万里
我们的余生。
Whoa! Ah!
哇！啊!
- [whimpering]
- [呜咽]
[wailing]
[哀号]
- Ooh! That's a nasty low
pressure system from the north!
- 哦！这是一个令人讨厌的低点
来自北方的压力系统！
- [straining]
- [紧张]
[coughing, sputters]
[咳嗽、口吐白沫]
[retches]
[干呕]
- [whimpering]
- [呜咽]
- [panicked muttering]
- [惊慌的嘀咕]
Please, Mr. Doppler, don't
send Drizzle to cloud heaven!
多普勒先生，请不要
送小雨到云天！
- That's just an expression.
- 这只是一个表达。
He's not going anywhere.
他哪儿也不去。
- Phew, that's a relief.
- 唷，这真是一种解脱。
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
- I'm gonna drop him
in this dehumidifier
-我要丢下他了
在这个除湿机里
and dissolve him.
并解散他。
- [screams]
- [尖叫]
- Dissolve him? What?
- 解散他？什么？
Please, Mr. Doppler!
Drizzler's a good cloud!
拜托，多普勒先生！
毛毛雨真是一朵好云！
He doesn't deserve to dissolve!
他不配解散！
[crying]
[哭泣]
[somber string music]
[忧郁的弦乐]
- I've got zero visibility.
- 我的能见度为零。
Let go of my eyes, square face!
放开我的眼睛，方脸！
- [sobbing] Drizzle!
- [抽泣]毛毛雨！
[rumbling, mechanical creaking]
[隆隆声，机械嘎吱声]
- [straining]
- [紧张]
[thunder rumbling]
[雷声隆隆]
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
- [nervous giggling]
- [紧张的咯咯笑]
- I'm in the middle
of a severe thunderstorm--
- 我在中间
一场强烈的雷暴——
And we're bringing it
to you li--
我们带来了它
给你李--
♪ ♪
[audio feedback]
[音频反馈]
- Wha!
- 世界卫生大会！
[gurgling]
[淙淙]
[muffled whimpering]
[低沉的呜咽声]
Hm. [spits]
嗯。 [吐口水]
I'm Gale Doppler,
我是盖尔·多普勒
and I actually  am
the weather!
而我实际上是
天气！
[laughing]
[笑]
[thunder rumbling]
Huh?
[雷声隆隆]
啊？
Huh?
Uh-oh.
呃哦。
- Uh-oh. [grunts]
- 呃哦。 [咕哝]
♪ ♪
[all screaming, wailing]
[所有人尖叫、哀号]
- [shivering] My body is cold.
- [发抖] 我的身体很冷。
I don't want to be
the weather anymore.
我不想成为
天气不再了。
It hurts!
好痛！
[wailing]
[哀号]
- Excuse me, Drizzle.
- 对不起，小雨。
I don't mean to parade
on your rain,
我不是故意要游行
在你的雨中，
but could you please
put Gale down?
但可以请你吗
放下盖尔？
Whoa-whoa, whoa!
哇哇哇！
Whoa! [screams]
哇！ [尖叫声]
Ooh. Hm. Hm?
哦。嗯。嗯？
Huh? Oh, no!
Not more storm clouds.
啊？哦，不！
不再有暴风云。
- Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
- 哇！哇！哇！
[thunder booming]
[雷霆轰鸣]
- No! [sputters]
- 不！ [溅射声]
- What? [laughs]
- 什么？ [笑]
- [spits]
- Aw.
- [吐口水]
- 噢。
[chatters happily]
[开心地聊天]
- Holy hurricane,
they're Drizzle's parents!
- 神圣飓风，
他们是小雨的父母！
- Mm, mm.
- 嗯，嗯。
[muttering sternly]
[严厉地嘀咕]
[thunder rumbling]
[雷声隆隆]
- You know, everybody complains
about the weather,
- 你知道，每个人都在抱怨
关于天气，
but my next guests actually do
something about it.
但我的下一位客人确实这么做了
关于它的一些事情。
Did you two always want
to be storm clouds?
你们两个一直想要吗
成为暴风云？
[both inhaling]
[双方吸气]
- I'm Gale Doppler, and I could
probably use an ambulance,
- 我是盖尔·多普勒，我可以
可能使用救护车，
right about now!
就现在！
[yelps]
[machinery grinding]
[尖叫声]
【机械磨削】
[explosion booms]
[爆炸声]
[shimmering]
[闪烁]
- [giggling]
- [咯咯笑]
- Good-bye, my little
foul weather friend.
- 再见，我的小宝贝
天气不好的朋友。
I'll never forget you,
come rain or shine.
我永远不会忘记你
风雨无阻。
[kisses]
[亲吻]
- Huh? [whimpers]
- 啊？ [呜咽]
- Aw, thank you, Drizzle.
- 哦，谢谢你，毛毛雨。
Don't worry. I'll water him
and walk him every day.
不用担心。我给他浇水
并每天陪他散步。
- Whoo-hoo!
- Bye!
- 呼呼！
- 再见！
- [squeaking]
- [吱吱声]
- Aw, I'm gonna name you
"Drizzle Junior."
- 哦，我要给你起名字
“小雨少年。”
And I know just where
to keep you too.
我知道在哪里
也留住你。
all: Aw.
全体：噢。
[sizzling]
[嘶嘶声]
- Aw--[groans]
- 噢--[呻吟]
[bright guitar music]
[明亮的吉他音乐]
- [humming]
- [嗡嗡声]
♪ ♪
Good morning, Drizzle Junior.
早上好，小毛毛雨。
Not too hot but not too cold.
- Uh-huh.
不太热但也不太冷。
- 呃哈。
- [opera singing]
- [歌剧演唱]
[ukulele music]
[尤克里里音乐]
♪ ♪